<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shinyapp | Romualdi Lab</title>
    <link>/tag/shinyapp/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/shinyapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>shinyapp</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Research Group</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 08:00:20 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hud8b169d6400d4e9e77db720aa3284c6d_12325_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>shinyapp</title>
      <link>/tag/shinyapp/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>gINTomics</title>
      <link>/software2/gintomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 08:00:20 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/software2/gintomics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;gINTomics is an R package for Multi-Omics data integration and visualization. gINTomics is designed to detect the association between the expression of a target and of its regulators, taking into account also their genomics modifications such as Copy Number Variations (CNV) and methylation. For RNA sequencing data, the counts will be fitted using a negative binomial model, while in the case of microarray or other types of data, a linear model will be applied. In some cases the number of regulators for a given target could be very high, in order to handle this eventuality, we provide a penalized linear model that will automatically keep only the most important regulators. All the models are gene-specific, so each gene/miRNA will have its own model with its covariates. The package will automatically download information about TF-target couples (dorothea), miRNA-target couples (multiMiR) and TF-miRNA couples (TransmiR). The couples will be used to define the covariates used in the integration models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
